has generated $250 [music] billion with
a B in market value for Microsoft. Scott
Nadella, chairman and CEO of Microsoft.
>> Since you've been the CEO, three and a
half years, the [music] stock is up
about uh I guess it's about 120%. I'm
good for my 80 billion. I am going to
spend $80 billion building out Azure.
[music] Maybe after the industrial
revolution, this is the biggest thing.
That's our goal with our frontier model.
Our model should be the [music] best
model that they can use as a base. We
create technology so that others can
create more technology. That's who we
are. [music] We're tool maker.
>> Please welcome Satia Nadella.
>> All right.
>> Hi guy. Good to see you coming out.
>> Good to see you.
>> Good morning guys.
>> How are you?
>> Good.
>> Thanks for joining us.
>> Crazy weekend, but here we are. Do we
need to paste the frontier?
[laughter]
>> So, let's start with the common sense
part first, which is we should do what
it takes to build stuff that serves
humanity first and is in human control.
You know, it's kind of crazy that we
have to start with that level of common
sense, but I think it's a good place.
Then when I think about pacing whatever
the first thing that at least I believe
is the broad diffusion of this
technology is the most critical thing
because the benefits of this tech
showing up everywhere is really what's
all about right so at the end of the day
if you sort of say serving humanity let
it actually reach humanity in ways that
it serves humanity and that means you
got to have choice you have to have
compet competition. You have to have all
kinds of business models whether they're
open weights, close weights, what have
you. Then the other aspect I think that
is not talked about when we talk about
control is actually the control that for
example customers have, enterprises or
businesses have around this technology
because sometimes this is so opaque,
right? I want my privacy. I want to be
able to embed my knowledge in a set of
weights I control. I want to see all of
the coot uh that's being generated. I
want to use it to do fine-tuning of my
own models. My IP shouldn't leak. So,
there's an entire body of things that
nobody's talking about as much, which is
my I really want to make sure that this
tech is in my control. Then we get to uh
what is I think a real issue of safety
and we should take it seriously which is
we should take all the time we want uh
to test things. In fact I love this idea
of having third party testers. Oh wow.
You know I you know I grew up in a
company that's always done testing. Uh
so it's novel that we should say wow
they're having embedded third party
testers. Why not? It's a great idea. In
fact, the only thing I would say is we
should avoid like these, you know, cozy
arrangements of who's testing what, who
has access to what, and it should be
broad.
>> Were you were you surprised though when
both the essay landed and then it seemed
like there was a circling of the wagons
amongst the frontier companies? I
>> I I think that it comes my my suspicion
is it comes genuinely from this place
where when you start seeing in fact it's
fascinating, right? We are when you
start seeing reward hacking um and
what's happening in these environments
right with these agent swarms there is
the mundane there is some DevOps error
where somebody misconfigured
a container [laughter]
>> right right or these API keys
>> or an API keys or yeah exactly there's
no monitoring uh there's internet access
there's sort of classic I would call it
basic devops and then there is real
novel new stuff right which is what is
this uh reward board hacking uh that you
know with these persistent agents and so
on and that's a place where I'll admit
that the science is not there it's I
thought Yakob's post which is a good one
which he said he called it we're growing
intelligence not building intelligence
so it's an experimental science and so
the more experimental sciences uh then
you really need to make sure you're
doing those experiments in controlled
environments if anything the place where
I would love is taking even the hugging
face incident in other places more
transparency on what would it take in
fact one of the fascinating things right
now is the insider risk I mean think
about it right if you're sitting in an
enterprise this is all test time compute
by the way right so it's not like oh
it's going to only happen when in some
training run it can happen for a very
mundane task uh that I give one of these
frontier models inside an enterprise uh
where I say you know I don't I was you
know telling David this suppose I say
hey go optimize my working capital it
may fake my books uh right [laughter]
because this is like a new type of
insider risk
>> and so what is the way to do that I
would say oh go build a maybe a causal
model like a semantic model that
actually checks and verifies so I think
there's a lot of product building um I I
would say making things more robust
which is classic engineering that we
should be talking a lot more about
transparently versus saying hey this is
so mystical that you know we can't
figure this out. Do you do you buy this
argument that it's mystical?
>> I I mean I I buy the argument that we do
not understand the latent space. Uh
right other than I thought you know as
you said like do we understand the
brain? We don't. We do functional MRIs
and do neuroscience and we're trying to
figure this out continuously getting a
little better understanding. So I do
think that in that sense we don't
exactly uh have a complete un that's why
by the way I also I don't believe in new
release right so that's why I think
making sure that the coots are in
language that we can all understand in
fact they're transparent so that when
when I go back to an enterprise that's
using all these models and if you have
the full coot uh then you can
>> chain of thought
>> chain of thought and so then you can
really go look at it deeply in fact you
can have multiple models uh and you can
look at the coot across those I think
these are all things that I think will
become very important
>> satia you've worked with you've worked
with technologists for decades
uh and when you see as a leader of one
company Microsoft which has very crisp
communications with the public uh and
you see what's happening with Daario and
his team people coming out saying 10%
chance we all die uh what do you think
is going through those technologists
minds. Do you believe they actually
believe that this is going to kill
humanity or are they going through some
psychosis or are they seeing something
working on those frontier models that is
terrorizing them? You're not a
psychologist, but you have worked with
technologists for a long time. Handicap
what's going on in these organizations
that's all the making people feel the
need to resign and say we're all going
to die.
>> Yeah. you know, it's it's hard for me to
speak to what's happening in any of
these places, but let let's just say uh
how we I grew up even inside of
Microsoft, you know, for example, you
know, one of the biggest things you
learn as an early sort of engineering
lead is how to deal with a showstopper
bug.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. I mean, that's kind of like 101,
right? Which is why you're faced, you're
like, you know, you have a bug. Um what
do you do? do you stop uh and fix or you
defer or you go in and say hey this is
such an edge case that's kind of the
judgment so I do think and as the stakes
go up you want to like transaction
processing I remember working on
databases right you know wow like you
know you got to take very seriously any
bug uh where if the transaction is going
to get lost right data loss is a thing
that you stop the thing for so I feel a
little bit culture culturally in the AI
industry rediscovering maybe because
when you see and it's possible that they
see stuff which are showstoppers before
the rest and if you see a showstopper
stop the show um right [laughter] to fix
the bugs yeah when you saw the the
hugging face run and it was super
performative Dwaresh did his whole post
civilizations
what do you think what what's your take
on that testing they ran because they
could have run a test where they had
3,000 agents defend a bunch of websites.
Instead, they instructed them to hack
websites and you know the hiding of
information all this
anthropomorphicizing
whatever of the agents. I mean the way
at least I understand it was it was
actually you know basically trying to uh
do an eval uh for cyber gym and um as I
understand it given that eval it sort of
figured out a way to say let's just say
reward hack uh and that's what led it to
hugging phase in fact it speaks to I
think what's the pre you know clear
issue right now which is you can have
these things if they're are longunning
persistent agents
become essentially like new insider
risks. Uh and so that I would start from
the very basics of saying okay what is
containment look like. So for example
like one of the things that I think is
going to be really an issue and a thing
that needs great solutions is true
aggressive monitoring of agent activity.
Uh that's behavioral
>> evidence
>> evidence and so everything has got to be
auditable. uh and then every object it
access, right? If it goes and gets a
secret, oh, it's going to go chain a
couple of things, you should be able to
see it when it's starting to chain a
couple of uh vulnerabilities uh to go
hack. And so I think that these are the
ways um that you really have to sort of
deal with these situations versus saying
um in in fact I think the core of my
take is we will have to get the
engineering process around building out
this experimental science to be more
robust.
>> Yeah.
>> Thanks.
>> So I think I think that's a great point.
I love how you uh differentiated in the
HuggingFace uh episode between the
mundane things they got wrong like the
misconfigured sandbox and HuggingFace
had credentials just sitting in a public
repository and there was no monitoring
and then you have the genuinely novel
behavior, the swarms of agents, the
reward hacking. That's the stuff that
has everyone freaked out. I agree that,
you know, we have to now figure out how
to fix the bugs or, you know, fix the
deeper problem that's coming from that
reward hacking. What what do you think
that means for and and and and I think
to their credit I think what the
Frontier Labs are saying is we are now
going to slow down the pace of let's say
raw power and shift towards reliability
and predictability and you know what
they call alignment which I think is
good business practice I guess what do
you think that means for what we see in
terms of new products for the next year
or two does it mean we just kind of
improve what we already have or do we
see new capabilities what do you think
this going to mean A great question,
David. I I do think there's already a
massive model overhang, right? I mean,
um capability overhang in the sense of
the models are very good except the
broad diffusion uh requires a lot of
things, right? even requires uh
essentially if you're compressing
workflows and changing workflows to
happen differently u the amount of
change management that needs to happen
in order to even incorporate these
systems is sort of what's taking time so
to some degree I would say the and also
uh the the ability to create these new
form factors right I mean if you think
about coding agents and coding agents
became really usable when you discovered
that you could have an agent loop with a
file system uh and that was the
breakthrough that just made coding
agents work. Um and I think now maybe
with KUA right so which is with Astra
with KUA uh could be a way for us to
even do computer use or we just use long
trajectory tasks that can get completely
automated. So I think these type of
product innovations where the model plus
the harness allow us to do things that
then lead to broad adoption. Right? I
even go back to the chat GPT moment for
me, right? Which was it was that RHF at
the very end that made a chat
conversation possible. Mhm.
>> Uh and so I think that yes, so there's
some science, there is some form factor
that then leads to broad diffusion and
we now need to find the next level of
these things that are doing real work in
the real enterprise. Um and in that
context by the way the other thing is
it's going to be a multimodel world
right so at this point just out of
resilience right I mean think about
right every enterprise now comes to me
and says hey this model does refusals
here this model I want weights here I
don't and so the people are going to
want multiple models so one of the other
things that we have to get right is some
standards of interop right like even KV
cache like why the heck can't I use
multiple model families and have KV
cache reuse
uh right we've had document standards
you and I lived through it right but
we've sort of you know you kind of have
things that are interoperable in the
real world everywhere else so I think
this industry also has to wake up and
say hey in fact if I were talking about
the most important pressing things is
how do I have more standards on uh
interoperability how do I have a harness
that is external to a model so that my
memory is not tied to one model I mean
this is the first time you're going to
have a technology where your use of it
and the exhaust in the data could not be
yours. Uh I mean that you know like it's
like if I g sold you a database and said
hey the data you put into your database
is not yours and it's mine. It goes away
if I took away the license. How would
you feel about it? So therefore I think
we have some serious issues like that to
deal with.
>> I think that's a good segue.
>> Sorry. Let me just ask one question to
connect the um economic incentive
argument on what's going on. The
argument is the Frontier Labs are facing
token compression. 50 bucks for OpenAI's
kind of million token output versus I
think someone estimated Deep Seeks new
is like can go as low as 15 cents for a
million tokens of output. Let's call it
60 cents. 99% cost reduction.
If that is the the big kind of economic
crux of what the frontier labs are
facing, why would most tokens be paying
50 bucks? Most enterprises pay 50 bucks
when they could pay 60 cents for most of
their tasks. Doesn't that also beg the
question, are they in the wrong business
model? And I I asked this for you as the
CEO of Microsoft, what's the right
business model? Do you want to be making
the frontier model? Do you want to be
running the compute and charging for
rent on your compute? Or do you want to
be in the application layer? I know you
talk about this a lot, but I just love
your perspective from where we sit today
and how this all kind of
>> um
>> Yeah, I think the the fundamental thing
that I think we're observing is good
old-fashioned competition, right? I
mean, for me, if I look back at it, we
were we had like some real great closed
source assets, Windows. What was the
check against it? It was of course the
Mac, but Linux
>> uh we had a great closed source product
called SQL Server. What was the check
against it? there was always a
substitute called Postgress or MySQL. So
I think that's what's happening a little
bit of it is there's real competition
between closed source and the open-
source check is real. Um, and that's
good quite frankly uh because without it
I don't think we're going to have a
broad frontier ecosystem or broad
diffusion because otherwise we'll just
we'll be back to some uh you know
mainframe uh locket that's just not uh a
thing to your point about if anything
given that we will now hopefully
continue to have a much richer choice in
every layer. Right. So to me hopefully
we can start building these AI because
today the royalty of an AI product all
going to just the model layer doesn't
make sense if you really want to build a
product company right it just cannot be
in fact if anything like that's the same
thing right which is if you take the
database if there was no open-source
check on closed source uh the prices
wouldn't have been at a place where
people could have built the app tier
successfully and the with a margin and
so I think the apps are going to become
you know much more viable economically
which is great for the ecosystem. uh
there are going to be all these other
layers of middleware call it right which
is hey what's my memory system what's my
harness and orchestration layer so
there's going to be a very rich tools
ecosystem there the model companies will
do fine uh in fact you know the paro
they can manage the token pricing based
on their model family if anything I want
them to work on even the KV you know
these these standards
>> such that we can use multiple model f in
fact it's better for them in fact I
worked on Windows interrupt with Unix
first.
>> In fact, it was counterintuitive, right?
We used to think, oh my god, this
interrupt means we'll be less used
except we were more used.
>> In fact, we became weirdly enough
because there were so many variants of
Unix at that time that Windows interrupt
made Unix better and Windows better. And
in fact, we were able to penetrate the
enterprise primarily because we did that
interrupt work. And so that's at least
how I think about it. Satya one of these
we're in this interesting moment where
on the one hand you have these experts
asking for regulation asking for
oversight governance it typically always
leads to some restriction of freedom
and general society
are put in a position where now we have
to opine on whether this is right or
wrong but then on the other side most
people's lived experience
is not this magical productivity boost
of AI. At best, it's integrating our
Apple Eyewatch data to tell us why we're
sleeping less. That's like functionally
the bar for most people. Or why is my
kid an into chat GPT? Uh so can
you just help us bridge this? I mean,
you see so many enterprise applications.
Where's the magic? Like where is the
where are the gains in profits? Where
are the huge upside breakthroughs that
AI is creating that will somehow make
all of this tension understandable for
everybody?
>> Yeah, it's a great it's a great point. I
mean, I think this is the real question
which is how do we truly see this in the
productivity stats? How do we really see
it in the GDP growth? That's broadbased.
It's not just supplier
>> or supply side. Um I mean the the one
example that I I love and I get back to
in fact healthcare is a good one right
if you think about um health care and
even the simple doctor patient
interaction in our case we have this
thing called DAX copilot um that's the
place which is the most tangible example
I can always point to when a doctor can
spend more time with the patient caring
for them versus just the entry into an
EMR system that's a good productivity
gain If it can triage uh the inbox for
the doctor so that they can be more
responsive uh that's helpful for uh uh
for the patient and the care system the
administrator in fact keying like the
insure like because it's the
triangulation of the pay patient and the
health system. Yeah. Uh that's of all in
fact most of healthcare is sort of all
workflow cost. Uh so taming of that
workflow complexity that's a helpful
thing. But do you see that in Microsoft
with the people that you're helping?
>> Yeah, absolutely. We see that and and by
the way even in in simple co-pilot
cases, right, which is if you look at
the amount most people think about jobs
which I think there is going to be
displacement there is but the bottom
line is what are the new jobs that get
created uh is going to be one of the key
aspects of it. But also a lot of
knowledge work unfortunately is drudgery
right who you know I get up in the
morning and I think about like man all I
do is email triage right you know
>> uh what if uh even just these workflows
that are taking away time from things
that you could be spending time on
>> okay well you're bring you're bringing
up this great point if you go all the
way back to like the turn of the century
the industrial revolution when we had a
7-day work week you know a lot of people
forget why did we introduce the weekends
it was to sort of manage the tension
between different uh religious groups
that had to work in the same factory.
And then when you look at long run GDP
outside of some exogenous events, it
sort of is, you know, between two and
400 basis points.
>> And so what happens is as productivity
boosts come in,
>> human work steps back and you kind of
accomplish the same amount of work.
>> Do you think that that happens here? Is
that is there a risk that we have a
three-day work week and we're just still
growing at two and a half%. Yeah, that's
a great qu or will we find new things
and this is where the excitement at
least I have for what the real impact of
AI would be is instead of just thinking
about hey it has helped me augment some
workflow or simplify something that's
happening today is it inventing new
things uh is it speeding up drug
discovery um is it taking the u I don't
know let's again go back to my example
of okay the working capital management
of a small business has become so much
more efficient uh that suddenly it's no
longer just oh I have an ERP or a
QuickBooks like thing but I truly am
making decisions based on the ability to
introspect my invoices my emails and
what have you and some somehow optimize
my working capital that's productivity
that didn't exist and so I do hope that
we will start seeing GDP growth which we
did see in the industrial era um during
the first phase of it.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. So, so that I think is what is
needed, right? Which is in order for all
of this to play out quite frankly, we do
need to see at least 7 8% GDP growth
that is real and that's broad-based.
>> What's the what business is Microsoft in
in relation to AI? Obviously, Azure has
been crushing it. you're turning away
customers uh and you're doing $175
billion in capex buildout, but your
capex is far below what Meta is doing,
far below what Google's doing. They're
doing secondary raises and raising debt,
350 billion. The Frontier Labs are
spending 500 billion. You were so early
to the party with the precient open AI
investment, but then co-pilot didn't
exactly land. I don't think it didn't
get great reviews. You don't have a
frontier model. What's the business?
Please come back. [laughter]
>> No, but what's the business here? What's
the
>> Do you need to have a frontier model?
>> Did Did we tell you there was one
journalist on the panel? [laughter]
>> No, no, no. It's I mean I mean it
sincerely because I'm just curious.
You're a great strategist. We know that
about you. Microsoft missed the mobile
revolution.
>> Is Microsoft going to miss the AI
revolution? You don't have a frontier
model? Because I always found it
perplexing that you didn't. And what's
the strategy there in all seriousness?
Like do you think open source is going
to win? you should have that play.
>> Yeah. So, let me walk you uh through the
sort of where we are and what we're up
to on each of these. By the way, on the
capex side and the buildout side, we
started early. So we if you sort of
cumulatively look um it's a good I'm not
sort of saying you know right right now
speaking about a lot of capex is not a
feature it's a bug but that [laughter]
said but if you really go actually add
up the math uh given when we started
because we started multiple years before
people woke up to even actually needing
to build and so that's kind of one
aspect of it. The other aspect of it is
we are calibrating our capex in such a
way that we don't we don't want to build
for one or two customers right so we
want to build for the long tail right
because that's I think most important
and that's I mean that if you're a
hyperscaler you're not a supplier to two
model companies that's not a business uh
you have to sort of basically build a
system that is great for lots of third
parties uh and our own one in that
context we're pretty thrilled with the
progress we're making uh with even
copilot if you sort of look at the
subscriber numbers we gave which is this
is goes back in fact to Chamat's
fundamental point which is these are
real enterprises using it for real
workflows u and the fact that we now
have 30 plus million not over forum
remember the total knowledge worker base
right where most people talk about 3
billion people 4 billion people on the
internet the entire office 365 or
Microsoft 365 is the the the sort of the
standard when it comes to knowledge work
there's 450 million that's including all
students in the world
>> oh wow
>> right So when we talk like the market
quote unquote as defined is maybe 300 uh
250 even of real enterprise users and of
that we've got the penetration of close
to 30 million on that and it's growing
and so on. The aspect on the model side
is we're thrilled about obviously our
investment in open AAI the access we
have to their IP which we have for a
long time we're going to use that but we
are well on our way building our MAI
models right if you look at it we have a
flash cyber model that you know with our
harness orchestrating other models
outperforms
um on cyber gym even a mythos uh same
thing we're seeing in coding same thing
we're seeing in uh knowledge work right
So our goal is to basically hill climb
from the bottom by the way uh not
distilling anything. So from the very
bottom using our RLES our data uh and
then also have a differentiated position
with enterprises going back to
addressing some of the things that they
want which is hey can I have the weights
can I have the weights that I can then
add to my knowledge uh these are the
things that we will do with our
foundation. Your best advice I think to
enterprises is AI sovereignty is
important. Putting your data into a
frontier model probably not a good idea
and then you're going to be that harness
for them to to help them. So my
implement my advice is more like use all
but be independent of all. So for
example my asset test is you should
always eval
that matter to you right. So what's the
outcome you want? you should go run that
outcome through all the models. Then
here's the test I would do. I would pull
out a model and see whether I can retain
the eval. If I can't, that means you
really are dependent on something that
may or may not be yours.
>> Right.
>> Right. That's so so my fundamental
enterprise architecture would say you
should have a model system that
fundamentally allows you to be able to
continuously hill climb on your own on
eval
uh while using all models closed open u
if you want you can even fine-tune any
of these models but you can even
substitute models
>> s just to build on Jason's question you
had this um incredible moment I think we
put it here where you said you know
we're good for our 80 billion. But just
to expand the question, um there's
effectively this sort of bank of AI that
has emerged and there's this financing
mechanism that just is so important to
the entire ecosystem and now broadly to
the entire economy. But you've been very
disciplined. You have an enormous
balance sheet. You're also an investment
grade issuer. So you could do what
Jensen did, but you've taken a very
different capital allocation approach,
much larger bets, very concentrated, and
you've kind of stayed into your own
ecosystem. just talk us through your
mindset as a capital allocator at
Microsoft and that balance sheet. Yeah.
So the way I'm sort of looking at our
book of business whether it's the hypers
scale our model or our app tier and the
shape of the demand um and then what's
the way to build out for it. And so if
you think about these assets right there
are two classes of it. There are the
long lead um long duration assets like
the the land power cold shell let's call
it. Then there is the kit. the kit is
the short-term uh asset uh that you can
much more you know uh be demand driven
in other words right I have to forecast
let's say two years three year out
demand and then and then also
>> the kit means the racks the chips
>> the racks the chips and what have you
and that's 60% of the cost or what have
you right so therefore so what we do is
we go build as much um we lease we even
rent now right now we're even renting
quite a bit because we kind of were
short on supply uh But the overall goal
is to build more lease some and then if
really need to surge we will even rent
that's kind of on the on the on the uh
assets and then the chips themselves we
will try to be first of all make sure
that we're matching demand and as I said
my goal is not to have just two
customers three customers uh it's great
to have openi being one of our largest
customers it's great that they're
growing uh but we need more uh is the
kit over earning right now and do do we
need is the is the industry pushing for
diversification more silicon more memory
more vendors
>> yeah what's happening is the workloads
that are now at scale uh they obviously
grew up from what GPUs were there but
now the the shape is so well understood
uh that you're able to optimize for a
very different world right So you can
sort of start building
>> um and saying well you know there are
these multiple phases in um an inference
or a training phase so why not build
silicon that's optimized for these uh
and that's just going to lead to a
systems architecture that I think is
going to by definition have a lot more
uh diversity uh I mean I know you have
Jensen coming he himself if you look at
his own architecture is changing quite
drastically
>> quite drastically
>> um and so I think that there is going to
be a lot more choice even there in that
layer. So ours we have Jensen stuff
which is I think our primary thing. We
have our own uh OpenAI is building their
chip so that's also going to be there.
AMD is in there. So we I I my thing is
to run whether it's the OpenAI models,
the anthropic models or our own models
on a heterogeneous kit.
>> Sax I want to let you get in here before
we run out of time.
>> Yeah. So you know we've heard now from
the the various frontier lab leaders Sam
Dario Elon Demis that we need to
prioritize alignment like we're talking
predictability reliability robustness uh
as opposed to maybe just say raw raw
power. Do you think the Chinese labs
will follow suit?
I think that that's the dialogue um that
is I think should be prioritized right
so because at some level my own premise
would be that
that China should also deeply care uh
about the same safety concerns if the
United States uh cares about them right
why should it be different for them it's
not like they won't have the same
hacking problem
>> uh it's not as if uh they don't want to
make sure that their citizens um are
benefiting from AI just like we will
want our citizens to benefit from AI. So
I think that there's a possibility of
international norms around it. If we
really are concrete about what's the
risk, why is this risk so idiosyncratic
that the only people who are worried
about it is the Americans. Uh it doesn't
make sense, right? It's not like a thing
that is sort of said, "Oh, I'm going to
only show up in the United States. I'm
going to be something. If it is going to
go wrong, it's going to go wrong
everywhere at the same time." So I think
the Chinese should care. I mean they're
they are a superpower.
>> Well that's you use the word
idiosyncratic and I think that is the
right word is I don't think we know yet
is this um you know conversation we're
having in the US over the past week. Is
it idiosyncratic to us because we have
you know the strong I guess you could
say doomer type uh school of thought or
is it something that the rest of the
world will basically feel as well?
>> It's a great question
>> and if they do then presumably they'd
want to act on it as well. Yeah, I I
just feel my my take there is that we
are ahead
>> and we are who we are which is we argue
we sort of we compete uh we are more
transparent which is all by the way
virtues as far as I'm concerned so
therefore the fact that this debate is
happening here the world will be better
off for it right so to some degree us
setting if anything I would love a US
set us to lead in the norms that allow
us to defuse use this technology broadly
and create safety standards uh that work
for the world including China. But
>> what do you think we should be doing
that we're not doing and what are you
doing at Microsoft
to change the narrative the populist
sentiment that we have to shut down
super intelligence stop building data
centers
>> etc. So, so to me I think this is I am
squarely focused on one of the to
answering Chamat's question from earlier
which is whom is it benefiting and give
me concrete stories right uh we talked
about the productivity benefits a bit uh
whether it's in healthcare or in general
knowledge work coding but I'll give you
another example right I was looking at
data centers because after all we didn't
talk much uh today on that but there's a
challenge on how does one earn
permission uh to open a data center in a
region. In fact, we just have some of
the best longitudinal data now for a
data center we built out in Quinsey,
Washington, uh for 20 years, close to,
you know, 2008 is when we started it.
And when I look at that data and what it
has meant for that community, right,
where uh the tax revenues have gone up
12 times, uh the paidin taxes have gone
down by a third. Um the growth is higher
than Seattle in Quinsey. This is a rural
town. Uh they have a new school, a new
hospital, a new town center, a new
aquatic center. Wow.
>> Uh we have two and most people say, "Oh,
there not that many jobs." In fact,
there have been 1,200 construction jobs
in that region all through that 20-year
period, right? Because it's not like you
just build it and leave. You
continuously refurbishing, building,
expanding.
>> And how big, how big is that data
center?
>> Uh I think it's now going to be at least
4 or 500 megawatt
>> and it sort of will keep expanding.
>> Um and so so these are uh so that's a
real like that community. So earning it
like just not saying hey these are all
the benefits but seeing it
>> but how do you get people to tell that
story because that's what's missing
today is those stories aren't being
organically told and if a Microsoft
executive gets on stage and says don't
worry it's good for the community.
>> Yeah. No I don't think Yeah. So I think
storytelling is one thing. The other one
is I think we just need more people
outside of the tech industry to say yeah
because if you go to Quinsey Washington
they will tell you thank god for this
data center. It's part of like you know.
So to me that's like when it's tangible
uh like that uh because that's the only
way to earn permission because at some
level the skepticism of any of us in the
tech industry just saying things uh is
so high that I think we have to now do
the hard yards of actually doing things
in the world uh which allow people to
say okay I now believe you.
>> It's a new muscle.
>> It's a new muscle. It's a new muscle.
>> So I think you're a good spokesperson to
flex that muscle. I hope you do it more.
Thank you for being with us.
>> Thank you so much.
>> We appreciate you. [music]
>> Thank you, sir. Appreciate your time.